<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>serverless paper review on Vahab Jabrayilov's Blog</title><link>https://vjabrayilov.github.io/notes/tags/serverless-paper-review/</link><description>Recent content in serverless paper review on Vahab Jabrayilov's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 15:17:43 +0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vjabrayilov.github.io/notes/tags/serverless-paper-review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Go Serverless: Securing Cloud via Serverless Design Patterns HotCloud'18</title><link>https://vjabrayilov.github.io/notes/posts/serverlessdesignpatterns/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 15:17:43 +0400</pubDate><guid>https://vjabrayilov.github.io/notes/posts/serverlessdesignpatterns/</guid><description>Review Authors have a security background and paper aims at utilizing serverless design patterns in security applications. They solely focus on AWS Lambda, and assume that all the responsibility to secure lambda execution lies on the cloud provider. However, customers are also responsible to secure their communication. They briefly describe six design patterns and how one can use them to develop a security oriented application.
Periodic Invocation Pattern represents the kind of models that invoke lambda functions periodically by using schedulers.</description></item><item><title>Granular Computing HotOS'19</title><link>https://vjabrayilov.github.io/notes/posts/granularcomputing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 12:45:51 +0400</pubDate><guid>https://vjabrayilov.github.io/notes/posts/granularcomputing/</guid><description>Review This paper is by the group of John Ousterhout and introduces the concept of so called “Granular computing”. They define “Granular computing” as the collection of very short-lived (10-100 usecs) tasks. The other main properties are large scale(1k-1M cooperating tasks) and short bursts(1-10 msecs of activity). Authors discuss the challenges coming with the new concept and present a few initial ideas about the required infrastructure to support it.
In granular computing, applications are composed of a very large number of small tasks running in microsecond scale both in parallel and sequentially, spread across thousands of machines.</description></item><item><title>Will Serverless End the Dominance of Linux in the Cloud? HotOS’17</title><link>https://vjabrayilov.github.io/notes/posts/endoflinux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 12:31:36 +0400</pubDate><guid>https://vjabrayilov.github.io/notes/posts/endoflinux/</guid><description>Review It’s a very short read and one of the early works. The main topic of discussion is the shortcomings of the Linux kernel for the current serverless paradigm. They argue that native container abstraction is ill-suited to be run as a unit of execution for serverless. They show that bypassing the kernel with unikernels can yield at least a factor of 6 better latency and throughput. While the unit of execution in the cloud shrinks, the complexity of the kernel is growing.</description></item></channel></rss>